the issue of Jena Haspel to be head of
the CIA you have written a number of
books and specifically your book time
and the shadows is about torture your
thought yes it on what she has done you
specifically look at black sites I I do
specifically look at black sites I and
that is incredibly harrowing what is
very devastating about what this what
her nomination has done is is to
essentially rubber stamp the the use of
completely and utterly brutal and
harrowing modalities of torture on
people whether or not they're guilty
there's never a sort of a legal process
that will allow us to adjudicate whether
these people are in any way culpable of
anything and in fact loads of innocent
people have been subjected to these
black sites now what is ironic of course
is that Gina has balls confirmation
hearing what's happening on exactly the
same day that the British government was
apologizing was issuing an official
apology to abdel hakim bell hodge and
his wife apartment wood char and my
boots char had been four months pregnant
sorry she'd been several months pregnant
but for four months she had been held in
thailand presumably under the reign of
gina hospital while she ran the thai
black sites there now what her
confirmation should it proceed is going
to signal is that all of those countries
in the world that acted as black sites a
number of those countries that are
members of NATO and eastern their
Eastern European states members of NATO
but which are also members of the you
had the wrist slapped by the Ewing among
them most specifically Poland and
Romania but those that are not part of
the EU and were engaged in these kinds
of and and they allowed their
territories to be used as black sites
Thailand foremost among them but there
were others as well as those countries
that acted as countries of extraordinary
rendition for example Jordan Morocco
Egypt and in fact Syria even all of
these countries are essentially going to
see this as a carte blanche for
conducting torture not that they ever
really needed it but
essentially I mean one of the things
that one hears all the time in the
Middle East is well if the US is doing
it why does anybody care about why Cece
would do it and so I think that in some
ways it would be an utter travesty
although completely unsurprising if
Jeana Hospital has chosen to head the
CIA now luckily Lee we want to thank you
for being with us professor it's so as
University of London author a number of
books including time in the shadows
confinement and counterinsurgencies we
ask you to stay with us